

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Senior Digital Accessibility Analyst seeking roles in Software Application, Application Audits , Defect Tracking, QA Planning, Software Testing, Software Debugging, Accessibility Testing, Web Application Development, Service

Current Designation: Sr. Digital Accessibility Analyst

Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: TIAA

Highest Degree: B.A.[Arts&Humanities]

Current Location: Pune

Delivery, Java Script

Pref. Location: United Arab Emirates (UAE), United Kingdom

(UK), United States (US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Outside Consultant Industry: Insurance Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Digital Accessibility Analyst, Outside Consultant, Software Application, Application, Application, Application, Application, Application, OA Disputer Software Debugging Accessibility Tradition (Adultation)

 $Tracking, QA\ Planning, Software\ Testing, Software\ Debugging, Accessibility\ Testing, Web\ Application$ 

Development, Service Delivery, JavaScript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

### Summary

Result-oriented Professional with nearly 15 years of experience in managing front-end Web and CSS development & Web Application Development across software technology, financial services, and education sectors

Designed web applications using HTML, JavaScript, and other programming languages and creating code from scratch to export data, connect applications, and design new web pages and maintaining application software and other web-based programs

Supported multiple Agile development teams in a highly collaborative environment to remediate existing web applications Skills in creating, maintaining and modifying application software and other web-based programs

Akeen analyst with successful track record of extending consulting solutions for accessible, standards-compliant, and cross-browser compatible websites and web applications

Skills in translating user needs into universal and accessible information design, website architecture, and effective user interfaces

## **Work Experience**

TIAA as Sr. Digital Accessibility Analyst Jun 2017 to Till Date

Key Results Areas:

Steering efforts in providing specific guidelines regarding front-end web accessibility for in-house staff and external contractors, while, updating baseline guidelines for all web and mobile applications

Conducting WCAG 2.1 AAcompliance Audit and proposing remediation strategy, and both formal and informal knowledge transfer and mentorship

Extending support to multiple Agile development teams in a highly collaborative environment to remediate existing web applications

Coaching product, engineering and other teams about new and upcoming assistive technology and related standards and participating in the development of VPATs

Translating technical standards, legislative requirements and third party recommendations into specific, actionable requirements for development

Developing QA Checklist and Test cases for Accessibility Testing and participating in peer test case reviews, Defect Management in JIRA and Daily Status Reports

Conducting Daily Scrum meetings and Defect Report Meetings and participating in sprint planning meetings, sprint review and Retrospective meetings

Managing Adoptive/Responsive testing for mobile web app

Managing the software quality process involving review of product functions, test specifications & documentation, defect prevention, metrics collection, team leadership & analysis, debugging & resolution of issues

Monitoring project progress & outstanding issues and ensuring the quality & timeliness of the deliverables; preparing monthly dashboard, project health check metrics and weekly & fortnightly status reports as well as extending post-implementation support to team members by identifying defects, inconsistencies & errors



# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

#### BA Continuum Solutions Private Limitedq as Accessibility Analyst

Jun 2012 to Jul 2017

Highlights:

Extended additional auditing and proposed accessibility recommendations as needed for company-wide projects Appointed as the key member of development team, provided technical recommendations and accessibility oversight of user interfaces; work closely with UI/UX, product, and engineering teams to ensure that envisioned features are accessible

Suggested modest changes to existing applications to meet changing needs in regard to Accessibility best practices, standards and guidelines

Extended assistance in the development of VPATs for all existing products

Developed test protocols and conducted Accessibility Audits & Business use Cases and Scenarios

Conducted testing using assistive technology (i.e. Screen readers and magnifiers)
Performed Manual Code Review (HTML, CSS and JavaScript); adhered to the Section 508 of Rehabilitation

Ensured that the WCAG 2.0 Principles and Standards based approach were followed to review and Subsequent reporting

#### SAPIENT, as Interactive Developer

Apr 2008 to Jun 2012

Highlights:

Conducted website analysis and redesign - developed sitemap and used HTML, CSS, to create, and manage website

Created online branding by collaborating with stakeholders and business owners

Performed the audit of W3C standard and accessibility Compliance (508,A/AA compliance).

Performed Expert Review on Usability, recommended enhancements accordingly

Appointed as the part of BRD teams for gathering requirements of the project and evaluating the dependencies, use of technology with client

Communicated effectively with Senior Management and built a strong relationship with business client

Extended support over Mozilla and Safari+ web browsers while still meeting the original deadline and project plan for meeting customers' expectations

Resolved browser compatibility issues; prepared HTML CMS Compatible

Used tools for versioning (SVN)

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

#### UG: B.A (Arts&Humanities) from Himalayan university in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Diploma (Web Engineering & Multimedia)

^ Back to Top

# **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used	d Experience
WAI-ARIA, NVDA, JAWS		
Voice Over, Talk Back, Quality Center		
ALM, JIRA		
Microsoft Visio		
Word, Excel, PowerPoint		
Access, Outlook		
ADOBE ACROBAT		
HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript		
Microsoft Sharepoint		
MICROSOFT WINDOWS		

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english				
hindi				
punjabi				

^ Back to Top

#### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.